<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: quotes | Reflections of a scattered Mind!!]]></title>
  <link href="http://saiprasad.me/tags/quotes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://saiprasad.me/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-05T11:02:04+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://saiprasad.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sai Prasad]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quotes I like:: Vol. III]]></title>
    <link href="http://saiprasad.me/blog/2011/03/quotes-i-like-vol-iii/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-05T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://saiprasad.me/blog/2011/03/quotes-i-like-vol-iii</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some random quotes / one-liners, I liked.</p>

<ul>
    <li>Great minds are always feared by lesser minds</li>
    <li>... there's a gap between what science knows and what business does (Dan  Pink)</li>
    <li>All those who wander are not lost.</li>
    <li>What we have done for ourselves alone dies with us; What we do for others dies with them. What we do for the world is too insignificant to count.</li>
    <li>Even if an analog clock is broken, it shows correct time at least twice a day.</li>
    <li>A happy man is not the one who has everything, but who makes most of everything he has.</li>
    <li>Keep your face to sunshine and you can't see the shadows.</li>
    <li>Make sure the thing you're living for is worth dying for.</li>
    <li>Speaking without egos, Loving without intentions, Caring without  expectations, Praying without selfishness is the sign of True Relation</li>
    <li>I decided to send you the cutest n sweetest gift of the world. But the postman shouted at me sayin - Get out of the postbox :-)</li>
    <li>If you don't count any of my failures, I'm quite successful.</li>
    <li>To live is the rarest thing in the world. Most people exist, that is all.</li>
    <li>The biggest fools are those who seek an interpretation for everything</li>
    <li>You'll never have a quiet world till you knock the patriotism out of the human race</li>
</ul>


<p>You can find my previous favorite one-liners posts at: <a title="Quotes I like :: Vol. II" href="http://saiprasad.me/blog/2008/09/20/quotes-i-like-vol-ii/">Quotes I like:: Vol. II</a> &amp; <a title="Quotes I like :: Vol. I" href="http://saiprasad.me/blog/2008/08/19/quotes-i-like-vol-i/">Quotes I like:: Vol. I</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quotes I like :: Vol. II]]></title>
    <link href="http://saiprasad.me/blog/2008/09/quotes-i-like-vol-ii/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-20T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://saiprasad.me/blog/2008/09/quotes-i-like-vol-ii</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul><li>Footprints on the sands of time aren't made by sitting down. - Proverb</li><li>Know how to listen &amp; you'll profit even from those who talk badly. - Plutarch</li><li>Accept the challenges, so you may feel the exhilaration of victory. - GS Patton</li><li>If you want to succeed, you must make your own opportunities as you go. - John B. Gough</li><li>If a man wants his dreams to come true, he must wake up! - Anonymous</li><li>Blame yourself if you have no branches or leaves; don't accuse the sun for partiality - Chinese proverb</li><li>They conquer who believe they can. - John Dryden</li></ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quotes I like :: Vol. I]]></title>
    <link href="http://saiprasad.me/blog/2008/08/quotes-i-like-vol-i/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-19T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://saiprasad.me/blog/2008/08/quotes-i-like-vol-i</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul><li>Expect the best. Prepare for the worst. Capitalize on what comes. - Z Ziglar</li><li>In great attempts it is glorius even to fail. - Cassius Longinus</li><li>The trouble with our times is that the future is not what it used to be. - Paul Valery</li><li>Trying to forget someone you love is trying to remember someone you never met. - Angelina Jolie</li><li>Experience is not what happens to a man. It is what a man does with what happens to him. - Aldous Huxley</li><li>I don't pray for a lighter load, but for a stronger back. - Brookes</li><li>Time ripens all things; no man is born wise. - Miguel de Cervante</li><li>A great civilization is not conquered from without until it has destroyed itself from within. - W.Durant</li><li>The best way out of a difficulty is through it. - Robert Frost</li><li>Every accomplishment begins with a decision to try. - Edward Kelly</li><li>Happiness is nothing more than good health &amp; a bad memory. - Albert Schweitzer</li><li>Most people fail in life because they major in minor things. - Anthony Robbins</li><li>Pick battles big enough to matter, small enough to win. - J.Kozol</li><li>If you aspire to the highest place, it is no disgrace to reach at the second or even the third place. - Cicero</li><li>People generally quarrel because they cannot argue. - G.K.Chesterton</li><li>Millions said the apple fell but Newton was the one to ask why. - Bernard M.Baruch</li><li>Bring ideas in and entertain them royally, for one of them may be the king. - Mark Van Doren</li><li>The powers of mind are like rays of the sun dissipated. When they are concentrated, they illumine. - Swami Vivekananda</li><li>Always behave like a duck - Keep calm and unruffled on the surface but paddle with great vigor underneath. - Jacob Braude</li><li>The aim of argument, or of discussion, should not be victory, but progress. - Joseph Joubert</li><li>At times, it is better to keep your mouth shut and let people wonder if you're fool than to open it and remove all their doubts. - James Sinclair</li><li>A man may die, nations may rise and fall, but an idea lives on. Ideas have endurance without death. - John F.Kennedy</li><li>Always forgive your enemies - Nothing annoys them so much. - Oscar Wilde</li><li>Success is that old ABC - ability, breaks and courage. - Charles Luckman</li><li>If you would not like to be forgotten as soon as you are dead, either write things worth reading or do things worth writing. - Benjamin Franklin</li><li>A Ship is always safe at the shore - but that is NOT what it is built for. - Albert Einstein<br /></li></ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>