<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: technozion | Reflections of a scattered Mind!!]]></title>
  <link href="http://saiprasad.me/tags/technozion/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://saiprasad.me/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-24T11:13:22+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://saiprasad.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sai Prasad]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dr. APJ Abdul Kalam in Technozion '08]]></title>
    <link href="http://saiprasad.me/blog/2008/01/dr-apj-abdul-kalam-in-technozion-08/"/>
    <updated>2008-01-29T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://saiprasad.me/blog/2008/01/dr-apj-abdul-kalam-in-technozion-08</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dr. APJ Abdul Kalam visited our Campus NIT, Warangal (<a href="http://www.nitw.ac.in/"><a href="http://www.nitw.ac.in">http://www.nitw.ac.in</a></a>) on Jan 26th, 2008 on account of Technozion &lsquo;08 the technical fest of NIT, Warangal. Eventhough His stay did not last for much time, that 1:30 hr stay changed alot in NIT, Warangal.</p>

<p>The students who have attended his addressing are all mesmerized for His excellent, inspiring and thought-provoking speech. All the brains of those students started working in the right direction following his speech. Students started studying seriously instead of playing AOE, CS and watching moivies. They all are enlightened by His words. Hope this enlightment stays longer&hellip;
The glimpses of His speech can be found <a href="http://www.abdulkalam.com/kalam/jsp/display_content.jsp?menuid=28&amp;menuname=Speeches%20/%20Lectures&amp;linkid=68&amp;linkname=Recent&amp;content=672&amp;columnno=0&amp;starts=0&amp;menu_image=-">here</a>.</p>

<p>HIs Excellency, Dr. APJ Abdul Kalam also interacted with the faculty members of the College. His topic was VISION OF NIT, WARANGAL. He also gave glimpses of INDIA VISION 2020 and the way NITW could drive its students towards that.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;d like to quote a statement from his speech which really inspired me &ndash; &ldquo;The most important part of the education is to imbibe the confidence among the students is the spirit of <strong>“we can do it”</strong>.&rdquo;</p>

<p>His Speech  on &lsquo;Interaction with the Faculty of National Institute of Technology, Warangal&rsquo; can be found <a href="http://www.abdulkalam.com/kalam/jsp/display_content.jsp?menuid=28&amp;menuname=Speeches%20/%20Lectures&amp;linkid=68&amp;linkname=Recent&amp;content=673&amp;columnno=0&amp;starts=0&amp;menu_image=-">here</a>.
Hope to see more Kalams' in the future&hellip;</p>

<p>Good Day,<br/>
Sai Prasad</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Technozion '08]]></title>
    <link href="http://saiprasad.me/blog/2008/01/technozion-08/"/>
    <updated>2008-01-28T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://saiprasad.me/blog/2008/01/technozion-08</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>sorry guyz for keeping you waiting for almost a week time &hellip;&hellip;<br/>
The last week, it was a complete festive and a busy week for me (along with all in my college), for the wekend was Technozion &lsquo;08 the Annual Technical Fest of NIT, Warangal&hellip;.
The most important event for TZ '08 was the visit of the Dr. APJ Abdul Kalam to our college&hellip;
This visit was the main factor to attract large masses of people towards participating in TZ'08 making it a big success&hellip;&hellip;</p>

<p>But, coming to my point of view, TZ'08 doesn&rsquo;t deserve it.. The TZ website (<a href="http://www.technozion.org/">http://www.technozion.org/</a>) couldn&rsquo;t be worse in any dimension. No event was upto the point of excellence and couldn&rsquo;t reach the expectations.</p>

<p>But this time, the accommodation and other facilities provided to the visitors was far better compared to the last year &hellip;.<br/>
Anyways, the TZ is finished for this year and the organization of the fest for the next year is in our batch&rsquo;s hand&hellip; Hope we do better &hellip;. : &ndash;)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>