<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: review | Reflections of a scattered Mind!!]]></title>
  <link href="http://saiprasad.me/tags/review/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://saiprasad.me/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-04T14:10:26+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://saiprasad.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sai Prasad]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Just Friends! It got something !!]]></title>
    <link href="http://saiprasad.me/blog/2010/08/just-friends-it-got-something/"/>
    <updated>2010-08-06T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://saiprasad.me/blog/2010/08/just-friends-it-got-something</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you&rsquo;re wondering what it is, &lsquo;<a href="http://sumritshahi.weebly.com/index.html" target="_blank">Just Friends</a>&rsquo; is a novel by an Indian writer. I think it is his debut novel, but don&rsquo;t take my word on this. You need to google (or bing, for Bing fans) it to be sure. By &lsquo;It got something&rsquo;, I don&rsquo;t mean to say, its an awesome book. I wouldn&rsquo;t even say its a good book, its just another book (add some 18+ masala content to the recipe) . What impressed me in the book are the quotes (quoted by the author himself, I believe) in it. They are not inspirational or something, but I liked them (not that I like only inspirational, in general). So, I decided to put my favorites here and share with you.</p>

<ul>
    <li>Sleep is deadly and love is lethal. The combination is so powerful that it leaves you helpless, forcing you to sleep later.</li>
    <li>A sleepless night is a lover's right</li>
    <li>Restless nights, drowsy mornings, confused afternoons, lonely evenings...</li>
    <li>Eyes are like prostitutes - they reveal more than they can conceal.</li>
    <li>I laughed, she laughed. Problem solved.</li>
    <li>I smiled, she smiled. All problems could wait.</li>
    <li>You pose a great competition to sugar for its characteristics of deadly sweetness and mixing quickly and easily in unknown waters.</li>
    <li>I wasn't superstitious. It was just... love.</li>
</ul>


<p>In case they don&rsquo;t make sense to you, you need to read the novel then coz they all are situational, though you can identify the situations from the statements itself for many of them.</p>

<p>Until next post, have a peaceful life (great would be great, though)&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>