<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: TimePass | Reflections of a scattered Mind!!]]></title>
  <link href="http://saiprasad.me/blog/categories/timepass/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://saiprasad.me/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-04T14:10:26+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://saiprasad.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sai Prasad]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Square One]]></title>
    <link href="http://saiprasad.me/blog/2011/10/square-one/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-16T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://saiprasad.me/blog/2011/10/square-one</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You begin at the Square One, you go forward with hopes and dreams, and most importantly with no idea what the future holds for you. You go non-stop until that day comes when completely unexpected happens, and you&rsquo;ll be just thrown out back on to Square One.</p>

<p>You get dejected, depressed and lose all your hopes that everything got ruined. You live in darkness of the past, until one day you say to yourself &ldquo;Enough! You got to get moving&rdquo;&hellip; And, you start moving into that unknown future, with fear still in your mind&hellip;. You try to take one step at a time, but you haven&rsquo;t gotten over your prior experiences. Yet, when you start getting over past and start moving forward with confidence, it happens again! You&rsquo;ll land in the Square One again, now with no knowledge on how, when and why&hellip;.</p>

<p>This time, you begin your journey again into those unknown lands, but instead of fear, this time you have that strange confidence &ndash; &ldquo;Not to fear&hellip; I can get over even if the worse happens again!&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Geeks are awesome!]]></title>
    <link href="http://saiprasad.me/blog/2011/09/geeks-are-awesome/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-09T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://saiprasad.me/blog/2011/09/geeks-are-awesome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You got to love the geeks! For their unique talent &amp; ability to transform any topic (including philosophy) into a discussion topic of bytes, pointers, stacks, exceptions etc&hellip;. They can convert every topic in this world to their area of expertise.. :D</p>

<p><img title="A small GeekTalk" src="http://saiprasad.me/images/geeky-thread.png" alt="" width="680" height="527" /><br>
<em>A small geeky conversation from my wall on Facebook</em>
&nbsp;</p>

<p>Dedicated to the geeks <a title="Shrey Banga on Facebook" href="https://www.facebook.com/banga.shrey" target="_blank">Shrey Banga</a> &amp; <a title="Sharad Banka on Facebook" href="https://www.facebook.com/sharad.banka" target="_blank">Sharad Banka</a> :D :D</p>


<p><strong>Update (11 September, 2011):</strong> Updated the image to include a missing comment (missed earlier since the account was then in deactivated state..)</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quotes I like:: Vol. III]]></title>
    <link href="http://saiprasad.me/blog/2011/03/quotes-i-like-vol-iii/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-05T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://saiprasad.me/blog/2011/03/quotes-i-like-vol-iii</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some random quotes / one-liners, I liked.</p>

<ul>
    <li>Great minds are always feared by lesser minds</li>
    <li>... there's a gap between what science knows and what business does (Dan  Pink)</li>
    <li>All those who wander are not lost.</li>
    <li>What we have done for ourselves alone dies with us; What we do for others dies with them. What we do for the world is too insignificant to count.</li>
    <li>Even if an analog clock is broken, it shows correct time at least twice a day.</li>
    <li>A happy man is not the one who has everything, but who makes most of everything he has.</li>
    <li>Keep your face to sunshine and you can't see the shadows.</li>
    <li>Make sure the thing you're living for is worth dying for.</li>
    <li>Speaking without egos, Loving without intentions, Caring without  expectations, Praying without selfishness is the sign of True Relation</li>
    <li>I decided to send you the cutest n sweetest gift of the world. But the postman shouted at me sayin - Get out of the postbox :-)</li>
    <li>If you don't count any of my failures, I'm quite successful.</li>
    <li>To live is the rarest thing in the world. Most people exist, that is all.</li>
    <li>The biggest fools are those who seek an interpretation for everything</li>
    <li>You'll never have a quiet world till you knock the patriotism out of the human race</li>
</ul>


<p>You can find my previous favorite one-liners posts at: <a title="Quotes I like :: Vol. II" href="http://saiprasad.me/blog/2008/09/20/quotes-i-like-vol-ii/">Quotes I like:: Vol. II</a> &amp; <a title="Quotes I like :: Vol. I" href="http://saiprasad.me/blog/2008/08/19/quotes-i-like-vol-i/">Quotes I like:: Vol. I</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Just Friends! It got something !!]]></title>
    <link href="http://saiprasad.me/blog/2010/08/just-friends-it-got-something/"/>
    <updated>2010-08-06T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://saiprasad.me/blog/2010/08/just-friends-it-got-something</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you&rsquo;re wondering what it is, &lsquo;<a href="http://sumritshahi.weebly.com/index.html" target="_blank">Just Friends</a>&rsquo; is a novel by an Indian writer. I think it is his debut novel, but don&rsquo;t take my word on this. You need to google (or bing, for Bing fans) it to be sure. By &lsquo;It got something&rsquo;, I don&rsquo;t mean to say, its an awesome book. I wouldn&rsquo;t even say its a good book, its just another book (add some 18+ masala content to the recipe) . What impressed me in the book are the quotes (quoted by the author himself, I believe) in it. They are not inspirational or something, but I liked them (not that I like only inspirational, in general). So, I decided to put my favorites here and share with you.</p>

<ul>
    <li>Sleep is deadly and love is lethal. The combination is so powerful that it leaves you helpless, forcing you to sleep later.</li>
    <li>A sleepless night is a lover's right</li>
    <li>Restless nights, drowsy mornings, confused afternoons, lonely evenings...</li>
    <li>Eyes are like prostitutes - they reveal more than they can conceal.</li>
    <li>I laughed, she laughed. Problem solved.</li>
    <li>I smiled, she smiled. All problems could wait.</li>
    <li>You pose a great competition to sugar for its characteristics of deadly sweetness and mixing quickly and easily in unknown waters.</li>
    <li>I wasn't superstitious. It was just... love.</li>
</ul>


<p>In case they don&rsquo;t make sense to you, you need to read the novel then coz they all are situational, though you can identify the situations from the statements itself for many of them.</p>

<p>Until next post, have a peaceful life (great would be great, though)&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ask your computer to help you in household chores]]></title>
    <link href="http://saiprasad.me/blog/2009/10/ask-your-computer-to-help-you-in-household-chores/"/>
    <updated>2009-10-22T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://saiprasad.me/blog/2009/10/ask-your-computer-to-help-you-in-household-chores</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Does this title come as a surprise to you? But, yes ! computer can help you with some additional things too (apart from computing).</p>

<p>With a small program, you can make the cradle (baby rocker) of your baby swing, without your presence. Shocked? Well, do you recognize you PC has a CDROM and also a program can also open &amp; close a CDROM drive?  Continuous opening &amp; closing of CDROM can help in your baby rocker&rsquo;s harmonic motion.</p>

<p>Check this link for similar innovative ideas: <a href="http://blog.makezine.com/archive/2009/08/linux_baby_rocker.html"><a href="http://blog.makezine.com/archive/2009/08/linux_baby_rocker.html">http://blog.makezine.com/archive/2009/08/linux_baby_rocker.html</a></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
