<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Personal | Reflections of a scattered Mind!!]]></title>
  <link href="http://saiprasad.me/blog/categories/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://saiprasad.me/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-24T11:13:22+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://saiprasad.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sai Prasad]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What do I regret the most?]]></title>
    <link href="http://saiprasad.me/blog/2012/10/what-do-i-regret-the-most/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-07T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://saiprasad.me/blog/2012/10/what-do-i-regret-the-most</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Its life.. Things happen.. Some things you never wanted to happen, somethings you never thought could happen, some bad things, and some surprisingly life-changing things&hellip; Out of everything, there is one thing I truly regret, wish it never happened &ndash; <strong>Growing up</strong>.</p>

<p>So, what did growing up do to me, you may wonder..</p>

<ul>
    <li>It made me a killer. Forced me kill <del>some</del> many of my own dreams.</li>
    <li>Showed me its not easy to make a choice, and later made me realize that some choices could turn out to be really bad ones..</li>
    <li>Showed me you could end up in a big mess even with no wrong decision taken.</li>
    <li>Its not impossible to repeat that one big mistake you'd never ever want to.</li>
    <li>Surprisingly and shockingly, you can't choose people. They come in to your life, maybe turn around our world without your knowledge, but you can't choose / control if they are going to stay.</li>
    <li>It made me experience that there are things you can't move on from, you just need to live with it forever.</li>
</ul>


<p>Maybe nothing else could express this better than this song.</p>

<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/3uFww9a3D4E" frameborder="0" width="420" height="315"></iframe>


<p>Now, I miss that little stupid and ignorant boy, who believed that everything could be simple if you don&rsquo;t complicate, and trying to find answer to his only big question &ndash; why does people complicate everything unnecessarily?</p>

<p>Ignorance is truly bliss.</p>

<p>Maybe its time to accept that life isn&rsquo;t going to be easy just like that, it takes effort, and more importantly belief that &ldquo;that some day&rdquo; is right around the corner, maybe.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
